The Register to the Betsy Jolas Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Programs, 1943-2010; Series V
  - 1969-1970 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - 1971 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - 1972 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - 1973 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - 1974 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - 1975 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - 1976 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - 1977 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - 1978 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - 1979 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - 1980 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - 1981 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - 1982 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - 1983 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - 1984 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - 1985 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - 1986 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - 1987 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - 1988 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - 1989 (Box 43a, Folder 1)
  - 1990 (Box 43a, Folder 2)
  - 1991 (Box 43a, Folder 3)
  - 1992 (Box 43a, Folder 4)
  - 1993 (Box 43a, Folder 5)
  - 1994 (Box 43a, Folder 6)
  - 1995 (Box 43a, Folder 7)
  - 1996 (Box 43a, Folder 3)
  - 1996 (Box 43a, Folder 9)
  - 1997 (Box 43a, Folder 10)
  - 1998 (Box 43b, Folder 1)
  - 1998 (Box 43b, Folder 2)
  - 1999 (Box 43b, Folder 3)
  - 1999 (Box 43b, Folder 4)
  - 2000 (Box 43b, Folder 5)
  - 2001 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - 2001 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - 2001 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - 2001 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - 2002 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - 2002 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - 2002 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - 2003 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - 2004 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - 2005 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - 2005 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - 2005 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - 2006 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - 2006 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - 2006 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - 2007 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - 2007 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - 2007 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - 2008-2010 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - No date (Box 45, Folder 11)
- Clippings, publicity materials, documents, and scrapbooks, 1949-2009; Series VI
  This series, organized chronologically, contains articles, publicity materials, press releases, catalogs, and other memorabilia related to Betsy Jolas's career. The last subseries also includes miscellaneous personal documents. The series is divided into four subseries: Clippings, Publicity, Scrapbooks, and Miscellaneous Documents.
  - Clippings, 1
    - 1949-1968 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - 1969 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - 1970-1976 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - 1977-1988 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - 1990-1995 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - 2001-2004 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - 2004-2009 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - No date (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Publicity materials, 2
    - 1978-1995 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      Includes Schliemann press book, posters, and various publicity.
    - 1995-2010 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Oversize posters for Peniche Opera (2010) and Opera de Lyon (1995).
  - Personal and Miscellaneous Documents (Box 46, Folder 11)
    Personal and honorarium receipts, government documents, American saving bonds, Francs.
  - Scrapbooks, 3
    - 1964-1973 (Box 47)
    - 1969-1988 (Box 47)
    - 1985-1994 (Box 48)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 48)
- Journals and pocket calendars, 1940-1993; Series VII
  This series is divided into two subseries, each organized by date. The Calendars subseries contains pocket calendars, address books, and compositional timelines. Some of the calendars include rehearsal times, concert setup, compositional notes and personal thoughts. Correspondence kept with the calendars is included in this subseries.
  - Journals, 1940-1984; 1
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access to the journals is restricted until the death of Betsy Jolas.
    - 1940 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - 1943-1950 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - 1984 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - 1984 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - 1964-1998 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Pocket calendars, 1946-1993; 2
    - 1946 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - 1956 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - 1962-1964 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - 1970 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - 1974 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - 1975 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - 1976 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - 1977 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - 1978 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - 1979 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - 1980 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - 1981 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - 1982 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - 1987-1989 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - 1990 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - 1993 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - 2004-2007, no date (Box 51, Folder 11)
      Includes composition planning calendar
- Photographs, 1926-2006; Series VIII
  This series is divided into the following subseries: Jolas alone; Jolas with significant musical figures; Jolas with groups; Family; and Photos of others. Photographic prints constitute the bulk of the series. Camera film and slides have been digitized, and are indicated within the series by printed contact sheets.
  - Jolas alone, 1926-2006; 1
    - 1920-1939 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 1940-1949 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - 1960-1979 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - 1980-1999 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - 2000-2009 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Oversize photos, circa 1990, circa 2005 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Jolas with significant musical figures, 2
    - Amy, Gilbert; Antoniou, Theodore; Auric, Georges; Berio, Luciano; Bon, André; Boulez, Pierre; Boucourechliev, André; Carter, Elliott; Casadesus, Gaby; Copland, Aaron; Christie, William & Les Arts Florissants; Schuller, Gunther (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Darasse, Xavier; Dutilleux, Henri; Druckman, Jacob; Gerard, Yves; Gottlieb, Jay; Guezec, Jean-Pierre (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Helffer, Claude; Leduc, Jean; Ligeti; Györgi; Messiaen, Olivier; Milhaud, Darius; Perlis, Vivian (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Rands, Bernard; Riemann, Aribert; Riopell, Jean-Paul; Samuel, Claude; Sarasse, Xavier; Schuller, Gunther; Stockhausen, Karlheinz; Xenakis, Yannis (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Jolas with groups, 1939-2004; 3
    - 1939-1954 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - 1966-1975 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - 1978-1990 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - 1991-1996 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - 1998-2000 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - 2001-2004 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Family, 1912-2001; 4
    - Jolas and family, 1
      - 1912-1937 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - 1942-1968 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - 1970-2001 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - No date (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Jolas and Gabriel Illouz, 2
      - 1977-1989 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Photos of others, 1945-1989; 5
    - 1945-1989 (Box 54, Folder 6)
- Awards and degrees, 1940-2003; Series IX
  This series contains Betsy Jolas's awards, degrees, and related materials, organized by date. Awards include her 2001 Ordre National du Mérite and her 1996 Legion d'Honneur as well as programs and award certificates for membership induction into the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1995) and the American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters (1983). Degrees include her Bachelor of Arts degree from Bennington College (1946) and her Dalcroze School of Music certification (1945). Also included are a Livret Scolaire (Student Report Book) from the Lycée Française de New York (1940-1942), and a French translation of her birth certificate (1946).
  - Award certificates, 1969-2003 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    Arrangement
    Three award certificates are rolled up, and included in this box.
  - Degree certificates, 1940-1953 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    Includes Betsy Jolas' Livret Scholaire (1940-42).
- Sound recordings and media, Series X
  - Test pressings, transcription discs and promotional discs, A
    - D'un opera de voyage, circa 1950; 7" commercial 33rpm disc, promotional copy (Box 55, Folder 1)
      "Impact de la musique contemporaine", Orchestre du Domaine Musical, Dir. Gilbert Amy
    - Dans la chaleur vacante, circa 1935 - 1955; 12" shellac single-sided transcription disc, 78rpm (Box 55, Folder 6)
      Andre du Bouchet, author
    - Chansons pour Paule, Dialogue alto hautbois, circa 1950s; 8" aluminum-core test pressing [33rpm] (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Le kiosque d'orphee
      Disc is currently unplayable.
    - Side 1: Figures I; Side 2: Figures I (mauvaise version), circa 1950s; 10" aluminum-core test pressing, 33rpm (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - I. Bid Adieu, II. Anna Livia (copie de 78 tours); I. Anna Livia Copie non filles de 33t., circa 1950s; 10" aluminum-core transcription disc, 33rpm (Box 55, Folder 4)
      microsillon service
      Disc is damaged, but likely playable.
    - To everything there is a season, circa 1950; 10" aluminum-core transcription disc [33rpm] (Box 55, Folder 5)
      Bennington chorus, Paul Boepple
    - La nuit n'est courte le vers, circa 1950; 12" shellac transcription disc [78rpm] (Box 55, Folder 7)
      Madrigal fur Marcel [Courard]
    - Madrigal, circa 1950; 12" shellac transcription disc [78rpm] (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - a. Quatour II b. Herma, circa 1968; 12" vinyl test pressing[?] [33rpm] (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Sonate a 12, 1972; 12" vinyl test pressing [33rpm] (Box 55, Folder 10)
      Barclay
    - Trifolium, circa 1940s-1950s; 12" aluminum-core test pressing [78rpm] (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Trifolium 3e mvt, circa 1940s-1950s; 12" aluminum-core single-sided test pressing [78rpm] (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Trio vl, piano, ve, circa 1943; 12" aluminum-core single-sided transcription disc [78rpm] (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Reel-to-reel tapes, B
    - Aimee, 1980; 10" reel-to-reel tape (Box 56, Item barcode 39002126526921)
    - Lecon d'analyse, 1984; 10" reel-to-reel tape (Box 56, Folder 2)
      Symphonie pour instruments a vent - Stravinsky
    - Le Cyclope, circa 1987; 11" reel-to-reel tape (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Dans la chaleur vacante, Josephine Baker, no date; 7.25" reel-to-reel tape (Box 56, Folder 4)
      "copie" magnetic tape.
      Tape has no spool.
    - Dans la chaleur vacante, Quatuor II, 1966; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 8)
      interviews sur
    - Dans la chaleur vacante, no date; 8.5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 7)
      pour Prix Italia
    - D'un opera du voyage, circa 1968; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 20)
      Ades 17001
    - D'un opera de voyage, 1967; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 16)
      dir: Michael [Gielen]
    - Generique Geijy, 1968; 4.5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Points d'or, 1985; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 56, Folder 6)
      Claude Delangle: saxophones, N.O.P. dir: Yves Pnin
    - Le Troyennes, circa 1940s-1960s; 11" reel-to-reel tape (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - 3 Recontres, 1974; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Trio for strings, orchestra radio Strasbourg, dir. R. Albin
    - 3 Etudes campanaires, 1980; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 2)
      au clavier: Renaud Gagneux
    - Quatre Plages, 1968; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 3)
      orch. de chambre de l'ORTF. Dir. Andre Girard
    - Quatre Plages, circa 1960s-1980s; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 4)
      B.B.C. orchestra, dir. Gilbert Amy
    - 5 poemes de Jacques Dupin, 1959; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 5)
      version avec orchestra supprimee
    - 5 poemes de Jacques Dupin, 1978; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 2)
      Claude Giroux, Betsy Jolas piano, Radio France
    - La Ponie, circa 1950s; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Caprice a 2 voix, circa 1970s-1980s; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - J.D.E., Entratien d'Amiens, 1968, 1969; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - J.D.E., 1966; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Episode Fusain, 1976; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 10)
      Heinryk Switzer, copy of WBAI concert
    - Fusain, 1972; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 9)
      Pierre [Yves] Artaud
    - Etats, 1979; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 11)
      University of Iowa Recording Studios
    - Frauenleben, 1993; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Granny (some of it excellent) with piano in Cherence, 1963; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 13)
      Maria J. Evarts
    - How Now, 1981; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 14)
      Yale, concert performance
    - How Now, 1973–1974; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 10)
      Octuor de Paris
    - Perspectives du 20th siecle, journee Betsy Jolas, 1978; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 15)
      interviews and performances
    - Perspectives du 20th siecle, Mots de Betsy Jolas, 1978; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Messe, 1945; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Motet II, 1984; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 17)
      interview par Georges Leon
    - Musique d'hiver, 1971; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 18)
      Xavier Darasse: organ, Orch. Du Sudwertfunk de Baden Baden. Dir: Ernest Bour, Studio Hans Rosband
    - Musique du notre temps, 1975; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Phonotheque nationale, Betsy Jolas, 1969; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - Quatre duos, 1980; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 1)
      Serge Collot, Daniele Bellik
    - Quatre duos, 1979; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 22)
      Collot Decrept
    - Quatuor III, 1974; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 23)
      9 Etudes
    - Quatuor III, 1974; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 24)
      first performance by the Concord String quartet
    - Quatuor II, 1967; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 25)
      Pathe Marioni CVB 2190, Mady Mesple
    - Quatuor II, 1966; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 20)
      Extrait du "Domaine Musical" BBC, Mady Mesple, Le trio a cords Francais
    - Interview Royan, 1967; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Musique du film Rhumatologie, 1958, 1960, 1964; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 58, Folder 2)
      Danse et affections rhumatismals, episode flute seule
    - Signets, 1987; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 58, Folder 3)
      Helge Anthony
    - Sonate a 12, 1971; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Sonate pour alto seul, 1953–1954; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 58, Folder 4)
      M. Th. Chailley
    - La deuxieme existense du camp de tatenberg, 1962; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 58, Item barcode 39002126526939)
      Armand Gatte
    - La Tempete, no date; 6" reel-to-reel tape and 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 58, Folder 6,7)
      for TV
    - La Tempete, no date; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 58, Folder 8)
      for TV, contains notes
    - La Tempete, no date; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - Voix Premieres, no date; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Voix Premieres, no date; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 57, Folder 26)
    - 11 Lieder pour trompette et orchestra, 1982; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 3)
      Pierre Thibaud, N.O.P. dir. Denis Cohen
    - Ajax, 1960; 6" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 4)
      musique du scene, text
    - Autour, circa 1970s; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 5)
      Elizabeth Chojnaka: clavecin, Erato
    - Chanson d'approche, circa 1970s; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 6)
      Musique du jour, Monique Haas: piano, Bernard [Focroulles]
    - Musique pour film enfant, 1963; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 8)
      Il Signore di Campangna
    - Liring Ballade, 1980; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 13)
      John Ostendorf: baryton, Orch. Phil. De Lille, dir. Jacques Mercier
    - Mots, 1968; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 14)
      Ensemble polyphonique et instr. Dir: Jean Lamy
    - L'oeil egare dans les plis de l'obeissance au vent, 1967; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - O Wall, 1976; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 17)
      premiere Lincoln Center chamber music ensemble
    - Plupart du Temps, no date; 5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 18)
      Betsy Jolas, piano
    - [Prie] Italia, no date; 8.5" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Side 1: Symphonie; Side 2: Quatuor I, 1959; 7" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 22)
      copy of LE11450
    - Tales of a summer sea, 1983; 6" reel-to-reel tape (Box 59, Folder 23)
      Orchestra Philharmonique de Radio France, dir. Gilbert Amy
  - Cassette Tapes, C
    - Bach, no date; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Black and Blue, 1993; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 2)
      Betsy Jolas-Antoine Illouz, émission, F. Culture
    - Composer Aujourd'hui, no date; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 3)
      Sommaire side A, Betsy Jolas, Entretien et Musique
    - Euphonia, 1996; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 4)
      Filiation, Betsy Jolas, Antoine Illouz
    - Encounters with composers, 1985; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 5)
      Jolas Concert 4-2-85, Boston University, Caprice 1v, Quatuor III
    - French Culture 1-5, 1990; 5 cassette tapes (Box 62, Folder 6,7,8,9,10)
      Rythme et Raison
    - France Culture, 2004; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 11)
      Betsy Jolas avec D. Cohen Levinas
    - Figures, 1958; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 12)
      Ensemble de musique contemporaire de l'universite de California du sud Espace Interdisciplinaire
    - In Tune, 1996; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 13)
      BBC 1996
    - Interview - BBC World, 1992; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 14)
      Russian Service
    - Inverview - Emission radio, 1990; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 15)
      2 Faces
    - What matters, no date; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 16)
      Kentucky Humanities Center, in English
    - Votre Mozart, 1991; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Stage 84 Ircam, 1985; cassette tape (Box 62, Folder 18)
      Emission "saxophone" interviews
    - Motet II, no date; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 1)
      D'un opera de poupea (extr); Quatre duos (L'Ardente); Serge Collot, alto; Sylvia [Decregt], piano. Note attached: "Motet II only, beginning, Radio France recording"
    - Motet III, no date; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 2)
      Scansion Lucrece
    - Motet IV, cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 3)
      Texte, Scansion latine-italienne, Lecteur Mario Caroli
    - Schliemann, 1995; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 4)
      "naissance d'un opera": Schliemann; France Culture; par D.C. Lavinas avec Betsy Jolas et Henri Dutilleux
    - Schliemann 1, 1988; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 5)
      presentation premiere; Sylvia Leroy, Laurence Monteyrol, Olivier Laloutte, Fumie Ito, Betsy Jolas, Antoine [Vivez], Cecile Frankel, Georges Goubert, Elizabeth Leonetti Gisele Barrean
    - Schliemann 2, 1988; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 6)
      côté suite
    - Schliemann 3, 1988; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 7)
      Act III Chanteurs
    - Schliemann 4, 1988; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 8)
      Côté 1 Suite, Livret Page 98
    - Schliemann, 1990; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 9)
      Opera Bastille (studio)
    - Schliemann, 1988; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 10)
      Act II (extraits)
    - Radio France interview - Schliemann, 1995; cassette tape (Box 63, Folder 11)
      en allemand
  - CDs, D
    - A voix nue, 1-2, 3-4, 5, 2006; CD (Box 64, Folder 1,2,3)
      France Culture
    - Comme il vois plaira, 1/3, 2004; CD (Box 64, Folder 4)
      Charles Sigel recoit Betsy Jolas, Episode 1, Duos Lasso, Come Follow, Quatuor II
    - Comme il vous plaira, 2/3, 2004; CD (Box 64, Folder 5)
      Signets, Musique d'hiver, Points d'or
    - Comme il voux plaira, 3/3, 2004; CD (Box 64, Folder 6)
      [Lovely], Motet III, Stances
    - Betsy Jolas, 1986; CD Sleeve (Missing CD) (Box 64, Folder 13)
      Stances, Points D'Aube, J.D.E. D'un Opera de Voyage. Marius Constant, Gilber Amy, Serge Collot, Claude Helffer. Disques Ades.
    - Bonheur des gammes, 2006; CD (Box 64, Folder 7)
      Sonata a 12, Mots (en 2 partes), Copie emission. Betsy Jolas/J.P. Derrien, France Musique
    - Bonheur des gammes, 2006; CD (Box 64, Folder 8)
      Copie emission, Stances, Musique d'hiver, B. Jolas/J.P. Derrien, France Musique
    - Bonheur des gammes, 2006; CD (Box 64, Folder 9)
      Copie emission, texte presentation de Motet III non [diffuse] par erreur. B. Jolas/J.P. Derrien, France Musique
    - Bonheur des games, 2006; CD (Box 64, Folder 10)
      Emission, Liring Ballade mais 1 seul canal. B. Jolas/J.P. Derrien, France Musique.
    - Bonheur des games, 2006; CD (Box 64, Folder 11)
      Copie emission, Quartour II, lovemusic, Trio "les heures". B. Jolas/J.P. Derrien.
    - Die Komponistin Betsy Jolas, 2004; CD (Box 64, Folder 12)
      Porträt von Walter Kläy. Schweizer Radio DRS, Studio Bern.
    - Motet III - Hunc Igito Terrorem, 1999; CD (Box 64A, Folder 1)
      Les Arts Florissants (Concert du XXe anniversaire). William Christie (direction). 33m38s.
    - Quatuor V, 1995; CD (Box 64A, Folder 2)
      Arpeggione Quartet. c. 19 minutes
    - Various Recordings, 2008-2009; CD (Box 64A, Folder 3)
      Bugallo/Williams Piano Duo: "Teletalks", "Calling E.C."; Haydn Theme from Symphony 104; Eisenstadt Trio: "Ah! Haydn"
    - Various Recordings, CD (Box 64A, Folder 4)
      Orchestre de Paris, Virginie Pochon (Soprano), Jean Deroyer (Director): "Lovaby"; Nouvel Ensemble Moderne, Sonia Wieder-Atherton (Cello), Lorraine Vaillancourt (Director): "Wanderlied"; Boston Modern Orchestra, Gil Rose (Director): "B-Day"; Eleves du conservatoire de Lausanne, William Blank (Director): "Sonate a Huit"; Boulder Festival Orchestra, Giora Bernstein (Director): "Just a Minute". 1h9m43s
  - DVDs, E
    - Betsy Jolas Joue Bach et Debussy, 2001; DVD (Box 64A, Folder 5)
      Betsy Jolas, piano. J.S. Bach - Le Clavecin bien Tempéré: Prelude VII; Claude Debussy - Des pas sur la Neige, Premier Livre: Prelude VI. Sonic Solutions.
    - Le Pavillon au bord de la Rivière, 1975; 2006; DVD (Box 64A, Folder 6)
      Theatre de Gennevilliers. Festival d'Avignon et Radio France. Running time: 1h27m
    - Une journée sur le Mont Ventoux, 2005; DVD (Box 64A, Folder 7)
      Documentary and staged performance of "L'ascension du Mont Ventoux." Perfomed by l'Ensemble Accroche Note. ARTE France, Sodaperaga, Metis Films. Running time: 52 minutes.